<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content on GRK 402</title>
    <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Content on GRK 402</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 21:59:44 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01. Sign of the Cross</title>
      <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/prayers/signumcrucis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/prayers/signumcrucis/</guid>
      <description>εἰς τὸ ὄνομα τοῦ Πατρὸς καὶ τοῦ Υἱοῦ καὶ τοῦ Ἀγίου Πνεύματος.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02. Our Father</title>
      <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/prayers/pater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/prayers/pater/</guid>
      <description> Πάτερ ἡμῶν ὁ ἐν τοῖς οὐρανοῖς ἁγιασθήτω τό ὄνομά σου, ἐλθέτω ἡ βασιλεία σου, γενηθήτω τὸ θέλημά σου, ὡς ἐν οὐρανῷ καί ἐπί τῆς γῆς. Τόν ἄρτον ἡμῶν τόν ἐπιούσιον δός ἡμῖν σήμερον· καί ἄφες ἡμῖν τά ὀφειλήματα ἡμῶν, ὡς καί ἡμεῖς ἀφίεμεν τοῖς ὀφειλέταις ἡμῶν· καί μή εἰσενέγκῃς ἡμᾶς εἰς πειρασμόν, ἀλλά ῥῦσαι ἡμᾶς ἀπὸ τοῦ πoνηροῦ.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03. Hail Mary</title>
      <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/prayers/ave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/prayers/ave/</guid>
      <description> Θεοτόκε Παρθένε, χαῖρε,
κεχαριτωμένη Μαρία,
ὁ Κύριος μετὰ σοῦ εὐλογημένη σὺ ἐν γυναιξί,
καὶ εὐλογημένος ὁ καρπὸς τῆς κοιλίας σου,
ὅτι Σωτήρα ἔτεκες τῶν ψυχῶν ἡμῶν </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calendar</title>
      <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/calendar/</guid>
      <description>Original Calendar Running Revised Calendar, Including Assignments Last Updated: 01/27/22
  Date Concept Quiz Assignment(s) Chapter     Jan.10 Introduction - Initial Review   1 thru 8   Jan.12 Noun &amp; Adj. Review   1 thru 8   Jan.14 Verb Review   1 thru 8   Jan.17 Prepositions Review   1 thru 8   Jan.19 Review   1 thru 8   Jan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 01</title>
      <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/01/</guid>
      <description>    Greek English     1 Ἀβρααμ Abraham   2 ἀμην amen, truly   3 Δαυιδ David   4 ῥαββι rabbi   5 Ἰακωβ Jacob   6 Ἰσραηλ Israel   7 Ἰωσηφ Joseph    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 02</title>
      <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/02/</guid>
      <description> Verbs like λυω    Greek English     1 ἀγω I lead, bring   2 ἀκουω I hear, listen to   3 βαλλω I throw   4 βλεπω I see, watch   5 διδασκω I teach   6 ἐχω I have, hold   7 λαμβανω I take, receive   8 λεγω I say, speak, tell   9 λυω I untie    Verbs like φιλεω    Greek English     1 ζητεω I seek   2 καλεω I call   3 λαλεω I speak, say   4 ποιεω I do, make   5 τηρεω I keep   6 φιλεω I love, like    Nouns declining like λογος    Greek English     1 ἀγγελος messenger, angel   2 ἀδελφος brother   3 ἀρτος bread   4 δουλος slave   5 θεος god, God   6 κοσμος world   7 κυριος lord, master, sir   8 λογος word, message   9 νομος law   10 οἰκος household, house   11 οὐρανος heaven   12 ὀχλος crowd   13 υἱος son   14 Χριστος Christ, Messiah    The most common word in Greek    Greek English     1 ὀ, ἠ, το the    Two more nouns like λογος with similar, but distinct, meanings    Greek English     1 ἀνθρωπος human being, person   2 λαος people (as in &#39;a people&#39; or &#39;a nation&#39;)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 03</title>
      <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/03/</guid>
      <description>Feminine Nouns    Greek English     1 ἀγαπη love   2 ἀδελφη sister   3 ἀρχη beginning   4 γη earth, soil, land   5 ζωη life   6 φωνη sound, voice   7 ψυχη soul, self    With α endings like ἠμερα    Greek English     1 ἁμαρτια sin   2 βασιλεια reign, kingship, kingdom   3 ἐκκλησια assembly (later &#39;church&#39;)   4 ἡμερα day   5 καρδια heart   6 Μαρια Mary, Also the Hebrew form Μαριαμ   7 οἰκια house, household   8 ὡρα hour, occasion    With mixed endings    Greek English     1 δοξα splendour, glory   2 θαλασσα sea, lake    Neuter nouns like ἐργον    Greek English     1 βιβλιον book, scroll   2 δαιμονιον demon   3 ἐργον work, deed   4 εὐαγγελιον good news, gospel   5 ἱερον temple   6 πλοιον boat   7 προσωπον face   8 σαββατον Sabbath   9 σημειον sign, miracle   10 τεκνον child    Very Important Word    Greek English     1 αὐτος αὐτη αὐτο he, she, it, they    Names    Greek English     1 Ἰησους Jesus   2 Παυλος Paul   3 Πετρος Peter    Another Verb    Greek English     1 πιστευω + dat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 04</title>
      <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/04/</guid>
      <description>Common Prepositions    Greek + Case English     1 ἀπο + gen. away from   2 δια + acc. because of     + gen. through   3 εἰς + acc. into   4 ἐκ + gen. (out of) from   5 ἐν + dat. in   6 ἐνωπιον + gen. in front of, in the presence of   7 ἐξω + gen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 05</title>
      <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/05/</guid>
      <description> Standard Adjectives    Greek English     1 ἀγαθος good   2 ἀγαπητος beloved   3 ἁγαιος holy   4 δικαιος upright, just   5 ἑκαστος each   6 ἑτερος another, different   7 ἰδιος one&#39;s own   8 Ἰουδαιος Jewish, a Jew   9 κακος bad   10 καλος beautiful, good   11 καινος new   12 μακαριος blessed, happy   13 μονος only, alone   14 νεκρος dead   15 ὁσος as/how great, as/how much   16 πιστος faithful, believing   17 πονηρος evil, wicked   18 τυφλος blind    Slightly Irregular Adjectives    Greek English     1 μεγας μεγαλη μεγα large, great   2 πολυς πολλη πολυ much, many    Important Conjunctions    Greek English     1 ἀλλα but   2 εἰ if   3 ἠ or   4 ὡς as, like    More Feminine Nouns    Greek English     1 Γαλιλαια Galilee   2 εἰρηνη peace   3 κεφαλη head   4 συναγωγη synagogue   Noun    Greek English      καιρος time, season    Verb    Greek English      εἰμι I am    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 06</title>
      <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/06/</guid>
      <description>More Verbs like λυω    Greek English     1 ἀνοιγω I open   2 βαπτιζω I baptise, dip   3 γραφω I write   4 διωκω I persecute, pursue   5 δοξαζω I praise, glorify   6 κηρυσσω I proclaim, preach   7 κραζω I cry out   8 πεμπω I send   9 πειθω I convince, persuade   10 σωζω (σῳζω) I save, rescue, heal    Compound Verbs like λυω    Greek English     1 ἀποκαλυπτω I reveal, uncover   2 προσεχω + dat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 07</title>
      <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/07/</guid>
      <description>Feminine Nouns    Greek English     1 δικαιοσυνη righteousness   2 ἐντολη commandment   3 ἐξουσια authority   4 παραβολη parable   5 παρρησια outspokenness, boldness   6 χαρα joy    Masculine Nouns    Greek English     1 ἀποστολος apostle   2 θανατος death   3 ὀφθαλμος eye   4 Φαρισαιος Pharisee    Neuter Nouns    Greek English     1 θηριον animal, beast   2 ἱματιον garment   3 μνημειον tomb, monument   4 προβατον sheep    Negatives, used in the &#39;other moods&#39;    Greek English     1 μη not   2 μηδε and not, but not   3 μηκετι no longer   4 μητε and not, nor    More Verbs    Greek English     1 ἀκολουθεω + dat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 08</title>
      <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/08/</guid>
      <description>Deponent Verbs    Greek English     1 ἐρχομαι I come, go   2 ἀπερχομαι I depart, go away   3 διερχομαι I cross over   4 εἰσερχομαι I go into, enter   5 ἐξερχομαι I go out, go away   6 παρερχομαι I go by, pass by   7 προσερχομαι I come to, go to, approach   8 συνερχομαι I come together   9 ἀπτομαι + gen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 09</title>
      <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/09/</guid>
      <description>Pronouns    Greek English     1 ἐγώ, ἡμεῖς I, we   2 ἑαυτός, ἑαυτοῦ himself, herself, itself   3 ἐμαυτοῦ myself   4 κἀγώ and I   5 σεαυτοῦ yourself   6 σύ, ὑμεῖς you (sing.), you (pl.)    Adjectives    Greek English     1 ἀλλήλος, ἀλλήλων each other, one another   2 ἄλλος, -η, -ο other   3 ἐκεῖνος, -η, -ο that   4 ἐμός, -ή, -όν my mine   5 ὅλος, -η, -ον whole, entire   6 οὗτος, αὕτη, τοῦτο this   7 ποῖος, -α, -ον of what kind?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10</title>
      <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/vocabulary/10/</guid>
      <description>Adverbs    Greek English     1 οὐχι not, no   2 ἐκει there   3 εὐθυς immediately   4 οὑτως in this manner, thus   5 ὡδε here    Nouns    Greek English     1 ἀληθεια truth   2 Πιλατος Pilate    Conjunctions    Greek English     1 καθως just as   2 ὁπου where   3 ὁτι that, because, or &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrickrcallahan.com/GRK402/resources/</guid>
      <description>Fonts &amp;amp; Typography  greektyping.com: Online program to practice typing in Greek New Athena Unicode: Standard Greek Font, distributed by the Society for Classical Studies SBL Greek: Font produced by the SBL-Font-Foundation and used by the German Bible Society. Designed for use with the Greek NT. Cavafy Script: Produced in 2014 by the Onassis Foundation, the Cavafy Script reproduces the style of Greek calligraphy practiced by the Greek poet C.P. Cavafy (1863-1933).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
